Finding aid for the Cheryl Nassar papers, 1960-1995 LSC.2229
UCLA Library Special Collections
Cheryl Nassar papers
circa 1970s-2010
1989-1992
UCLA Library Special Collections
Nassar, Cheryl
LSC.2229
1.8 linear feet (2 document boxes, 1 record carton)
Cheryl Nassar was a photographer and active member of the lesbian activist community in Southern California. This collection contains photographs and ephemera from lesbian and gay pride events throughout the region.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Provenance unknown, 2014.
This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW) and the UCLA Library.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9974047263606533
We are committed to providing ethical, inclusive, and anti-racist description of the materials we steward, and to remediating existing description of our materials that contains language that may be offensive or cause harm. We invite you to submit feedback about how our collections are described, and how they could be described more accurately, by filling out the form located on our website: Report Potentially Offensive Description in Library Special Collections.
Biography
Cheryl Nassar (July 10, 1944 - January 9, 2012) was born and grew up in Pennsylvania. She received a Bachelor's Degree in English Literature from the University of Pittsburgh. Throughout the 1980s, she was extremely active in women's rights as well as gay and lesbian rights organizations in Pittsburgh, Cincinnati, and in Southern California. She was the official photographer for many of the gay pride events throughout Southern California. She was also an avid collector of porcelain dolls.
Scope and Content
This collection contains photographs and ephemera by Nassar documenting events such as Orange County Cultural Pride, the Orange County Pro-Choice Clinic defense rally, Long Beach Pride, San Francisco Pride, and Christopher Street West Los Angeles Pride. Also included is ephemera collected by Nassar, such as t-shirts, jewelry, and buttons.
Organization and Arrangement
Material in this collection is organized chronologically.
Nassar, Cheryl -- Archives
- Buttons, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  Scope and Content
  A collection of buttons, including political buttons and buttons from gay pride events. Also included are a number of handmade buttons by Nassar.
- Jewelry, circa 1970s-2000s (Box 1)
  Rings, necklaces and an amulet from Nassar's personal collection of jewelry.
- T-shirts, circa 1980s (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  T-shirt from the 1983 Michigan Womyn's Festival, The 1987 Women's Craft Fair, The 1989 West Coast Women's Music and Comedy Festival, and a "Keep Abortion Legal" t-shirt.
- Professional Materials, 1989-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Pride Event Programs and Ephemera, 1989-1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Photographs: Orange County Cultural Pride, 1989-1994 (Box 3, Folder 5, Folder 7, Box 2, Folder 3, Folder 6, Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Photographs: Long Beach Pride, 1990-1993 (Box 3, Folder 4, Folder 6, Box 2, Folder 1-2, Folder 5, Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographs: Orange County Pro-choice Clinic Defense Rally, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Photographs: San Diego Pride, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Photographs: San Francisco Pride, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Photographs: South Bay Lesbian and Gay Community Organization, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Photographs: Christopher Street West Los Angeles Pride, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 8, Box 2, Folder 4)
- Resume and Writings, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 9)